# Tomomi Matsuzaki ux/Product Designer

mathie09@uw.edu 206.724.2352 tomomim.com

## **DESIGN EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance UX Designer - specializing in web design

Mar 2019 - Present (3 years)

- Establish project scope, design goals, and project timelines by working directly with clients.
- Build a site structure and navigation systems that simplify user flow using card sorting and an affinity diagram.
- Craft wireframes and provide visual design solutions to enhance the scannability and learnability of the website.
- Design and develop user-centered responsive websites with WordPress,
   Wix, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP and apply SEO knowledge to the site.

## Graphics Lead - UW, HCDE Graduate Student Association

Oct 2021 - Present (6 months)

- Create flyers and graphics that effectively convey messages and information to the audience and promote GSA events on social media platforms.
- Lead a co-design project for the HCDE program merch production.

## **Graphic Designer - Feet First**

Aug 2020 - Present (1 year 8 months)

• Design engaging infographics for social media, website, and policy papers to promote walkable communities for younger demographics.

#### **UX COURSE PROJECTS**

## Usability Study - Duolingo (non-sponsored) | Jan - Mar 2022

 Conducted usability tests on Duolingo's "learning a new writing system" tool and provided design recommendations to improve the ease of use and learnability.

## User-Centered Design - Safe Haven | Sep - Dec 2021

• Designed, prototyped, and iterated an interactive digital volunteer board application by closely working with the team. Led prototyping and usability tests to design an intuitive one-click filter and improve cross-device interactions.

## **Video Prototyping -** Grow Together | Nov - Dec 2021

- Created a video prototype to visually communicate the design idea and interaction with a smart plant application to the users.
- Received the Best Video Prototype award.

## **UX Web Design** - Seattle Central College | Sep - Dec 2020

 Redesigned the COVID-19 page on the college website by synthesizing user research findings. Built an information architecture and page layout that make the most logical sense to the users with an affinity diagram and A/B testing.

### OTHER EXPERIENCE

**HR Coordinator** - Eli Lilly Japan, Kobe Japan Mar 2021 - Aug 2021 (6 months)

Airline Customer Service Agent – ANA Fukuoka Airport, Japan Mar 2012 - Feb 2015 (3 years)

#### **EDUCATION**

# MS, Human Centered Design and Engineering

University of Washington, Expected June 2023 (GPA 4.0)

# Certificate, Social Impact Storytelling

Georgetown University, 2020

## AAS-T, Web Design Seattle Central College, 2020 (GPA 3.96)

**BA, Economics** Ritsumeikan University, 2012

#### **SKILLS**

#### **UCD METHODS**

User Interview, User Survey, Competitive Analysis, User Persona, Card Sorting, Affinity Diagram, Information Architecture, Storyboard, User Flow, Prototyping, Visual Design, Heuristic Evaluation, Usability Testing, A/B Testing

#### **DESIGN TOOLS**

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Procreate, Adobe Premiere Pro, WordPress

### **CODING**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python

#### **OTHERS**

Storytelling, Project Management, Customer Service Expertise

#### **AWARDS**

Hexagon Education Grant 2020